Mohamed Ibrahim

Profession: Computer/Electronics Engineer Nationality: Canadian

Address: 305 Edgepark Way NW, Calgary, AB, Canada, T3A4S8

PROFILE

The Industrial experiences of 8+ years, have given me the talent on computer systems, network systems, telecommunications, and software development. Designed and implemented an Arduino software using C, C++. I was working in Smart Labs Ltd, Calgary, as an electronic engineer. I'm experienced in understanding, testing and debugging complex systems at both levels of software and hardware.

SKILLS

- Experienced in computer systems, network systems, telecommunications, and software development.
- Programming using C++, Java, and Matlab.
- Designed and implemented an Arduino software using C++, Java, and Matlab.
- Software and hardware design review including schematics and PCB layout
- Test and Measurement Electronic and RF Devices
- Design Programs: Cadence, ADS, Eagle, and Orcad.
- Soldering/desoldering hole and surface mounted devices
- Holds valid Alberta driver's license, and held a security clearance

EDUCATION

2005

Master of Science in Electronics and Communication Engineering

Department of Electronics and Communication Engineering, Zagazig University Thesis Title: "All CMOS Digital Technology ADC for VLSI System Applications". In my MSc thesis, I presented a new Analog-to-Digital converter technique which is implemented using only digital technology. The proposed ADC circuit is based on the CMOS time to digital converter (TDC). The proposed circuit is simulated and layed out using Tanner Tools at 0.5 µm CMOS technology.

1999

Bachelor of Science in Electronics and Communication Engineering

Department of Electronics and Communication Engineering, Zagazig University, Egypt. Grade: "Very Good with Honor" (ranked 2nd)

Project Title: "Remote DataBase Accessing, with TeleBank Application"

The project has hardware and software design, with full programming by VC and VB.

WORK EXPERIENCE

2020-present

Loblaw Company, Calgary, AB, Canada

Personal Shopper

- Collect goods from appropriate storage bins, freezers and fridges.
- Unloaded, stored, and distributed goods to appropriate storage bins, freezers and fridges.
- Perpetual Inv: Bining, Picks, CVP, Throw and Damage, and so on.

2015-2020

Smart Labs Ltd, Calgary, AB, Canada

Electronics Engineer

- Programming using C, Matlab, and Arduino.
- The Schematic and PCB Layout design using Eagle, and PCB fabrication.
- Experienced in component reliable soldering/desoldering for hole and surface mounted devices.
- Exerted in theory and lab skills of implementing and troubleshooting basic digital logic circuits.
- Testing and Maintaining Electronic Devices using electronic tools: Network analyzers, Spectrum analyzers, Oscilloscopes, Multimeters, and Soldering tools.
- I have Experienced in using Simulation software: Cadence Analog Design Environment, Matlab, and ADS.

Mohamed Ibrahim

2017-2019 Walmart Sage Hill Supercentre, Calgary, AB, Canada

Associate in Dairy and Frozen

- Unloaded, stored, and distributed goods to appropriate storage bins, freezers and fridges.
- Perpetual Inv: Bining, Picks, CVP, Throw and Damage, and so on.

2012-2015 **Department of Electronics and Communications Engineering, Zagazig University**Lab Technician

- Assist in developing and instructing lectures, tutorials, labs, assignments, and projects.
- Experienced at component reliable soldering/desoldering for hole devices.
- Exerted in theory and lab skills of implementing and troubleshooting basic digital logic circuits.

2006-2012 Dining Centre, University of Calgary Calgary, AB, Canada

Baker Assistant

- Bake multiple baking products: Croissant, cookies, Muffins, and so on.
- Unloaded, stored, and distributed goods to appropriate storage bins and fridges.

2000-2006 Tempus Org – Germany/Egypt

Network setup administrator

- Building local networks, Setup hubs, switches and routers
- Network Software setup and administration
- Assembling Computers and installing Operating Systems.
- Fixing and troubleshooting electronic devices such as computers.

2000-2006 **Department of Electronics and Communications Engineering, Zagazig University**Lab Technician

- Assist in developing and instructing lectures, tutorials, labs, assignments, and projects.
- Experienced at component reliable soldering/desoldering for hole devices.
- Exerted in theory and lab skills of implementing and troubleshooting basic digital logic circuits.

INTERESTS Enjoy reading, walking, playing soccer, and travelling.

REFERENCE References are available upon request